This conflict began with but a single spark, and grew into a massive and terrible war.
The conflicting hopes and dreams of many different people have resulted in a great tragedy.
This is so sad and awful for everyone.
In addition to my grief at this war, I feel both shame and deep regret over our use of power for which...
Mankind was not ready, and so I hereby declare my succession to the Imperial Throne and take my place as Empress of the Verse Empire.
And also, I will be taking as my lawful husband, Count Cruteo of the Orbital Knights.
And as the Imperial Family of Verse, we wish to make peace with Earth.
In the name of the Empire of Verse, I command all Orbital Knights hearing these words, cease hostilities immediately!
What did she say? I thought that the plan was for Princess Asalem to found a new kingdom with Count Troyard.
But what about the U.F.E.?
We wait. Do nothing for now. Let's see which way the wind is blowing.
I should have known. After all, Troyard is nothing more than a lowborn Terran.
It's offensive to think of him in the Imperial Family.
What is this nonsense about?
Sir Harklight, return to base!
Lord Slain.
Why are they still shooting at us?
The Princess just ordered them all to stop fighting!
Now the Moonbase forces don't seem to want to stop.
Stay sharp! Heads up, everyone! We're not through with this battle!
Did you hear that?
Sure did.
That Princess Asalem just now.
Or rather, Empress Asalem. That was the princess that I remember.
You're right.
Everything Ensign Kaiska said to expect has come true.
That means that the ceasefire order was legitimate.
The enemies in front of us don't seem to feel like laying down their arms.
Are there any updates?
No, ma'am. Nothing at all. So it's follow last order.
Neither Moonbase nor Landing Castles show any sign of ceasing hostilities.
Current whereabouts of Empress Asalem?
Frequency analysis says it's originating from Count Mazurek's Landing Castle.
Has she abandoned the Moon? Or are we seeing a revolt?
Count Troyard, sir. What about Empress Asalem's order?
Order? I heard none.
Apologies, my lord.
What a surprise. Quite impressive of her.
Princess Lemrina.
The Imperial Family's blood is what's crucial.
As long as you can activate Aldnoa, are you not still able to make your dream come true?
Know that I will not be going away.
This place has become the only one I can call home.
So please let me help you.
Of course.
Your kindness is deeply touching, Princess Lemrina.
Shall we, then?
Yes.
So pretty.
Was that terrible to say, seeing that?
Out there, there's terrible beauty all around.
I have seen such things.
Truly? Like what?
The future.
All of it. The good and the bad.
While my vision was limited only to the immediate future,
I thought that I could see everything.
Some was exactly as I foresaw.
However,
I failed to take into account
what was truly important.
Load and rearm.
Sir.
Lord Count Troyard!
What is the meaning of this?
What is Princess Asalem doing?
My lord slain.
I am issuing orders.
Patch this through command.
And include Stygia's squadron.
Yes, sir.
Attention!
Everyone evacuate the moon base immediately.
Begin your surrender,
including the landing castles.
We are abandoning the moon base!
Have you gone mad?
Slain!
Princess Lemrina,
for the many wrongs I have done you,
I sincerely apologize.
But Slain...
May you...
have a long and rich life.
Harklight,
please escort Princess Lemrina to a shuttle.
Yes, sir.
As you wish.
No!
Slain!
Your Highness,
please come with me.
I won't go.
I won't.
Slain!
Multiple signatures detected
leaving the moon base.
Reinforcements?
No, Captain.
They're moving away
from the combat zone.
Thank you.
The Moonbase. It's blowing up. Did we do that?
Wasn't us.
Self-destruction?
Sir Harklyte!
See to the shuttle's defense.
Harklyte, wait!
What are you doing? Turn back! Your orders were to surrender.
Harklyte!
Stigus Squadron! Combat is not authorized!
Enemy reinforcements, 10 o'clock. Minus 10 degrees angle of approach.
Stand by to engage.
Retreat! This is not a battle you can win. Don't throw your life away.
I made peace with death long ago.
Grant me this one selfish act.
Surrender right now! Harklyte!
I hope you can forgive me, my lord slain.
But I cannot comply with your order.
Can I come?
All units scattered!
Bastards!
How could they do this? Damn!
Wait a minute.
I know him.
Huh.
You're absolutely correct, Harklyte.
We cannot allow it to end like this.
There is yet one thing
that I must do.
I've come for you, slain Troyard.
Let's settle matters now.
Hina ho, Kaisuka!
Oh, my God.
THE END
I THINK I KNOW THE ANSWER BUT I'LL ASK ANYWAY... WILL YOU SURRENDER, SLAY TROYARN?
YOU CAME ALL THIS WAY TO SAY SOMETHING SO POINTLESS, INAHO KAISKA?
NOT REALLY. I HAVE A DIFFERENT GOAL.
GLAD TO HEAR THAT... OR I'D BE DISAPPOINTED!
I THINK I KNOW THE ANSWER BUT I'LL ASK ANYWAY... WILL YOU SURRENDER, SLAY TROYARN?
I THINK I'M SURE YOU'RE NOT ABLE TO SAY SOMETHING SO POINTLESS, INAHO KAISKA?
NOT REALLY. I HAVE A DIFFERENT GOAL.
GLAD TO HEAR THAT... OR I'D BE DISAPPOINTED!
MY IMAGING SCREENS ARE GONE!
I GET IT. YOU CAN'T HANDLE ANY MORE HIGH-LOAD ANALYSIS.
TURN OFF PREDICTIVE IMAGERS.
I NO LONGER HAVE THE NEED FOR A FUTURE!
INCOMING! 2 O'CLOCK! ELEVATION 5 DEGREES!
COME ABOUT! ALL ENGINES FULL! HEADING 0-6-0!
AI-AI! COMING ABOUT!
LOAD CANISTER SHOT! FIRE WHEN YOU HAVE A LOCK!
NO WAY! ALL OF NOW'S COMBAT DATA IS AVAILABLE IN THE TACTICAL DATA LINK!
ALL UNITS REFER TO THAT-
YUKI! I'M OKAY!
ON BEHALF OF THE 37 CLAN'S ORBITAL KNIGHTS, I ASK YOU...
MIND IF I CUT IN?
WELCOME, COUNT BARO CRUZ.
INCOMING! 8 O'CLOCK! ELEVATION MINUS 25 DEGREES!
INTERCEPT THEM!
I'VE GOT THIS!
ONLY THREE ROUNDS LEFT!
IS-
INCOMING.
I WEARING
FIGHT WILL GAIN YOU NOTHING.
I AGREE...
BUT I HAVE NOTHING TO LOSE EITHER.
GIVING IN TO DESPAIR IS FOOLISH.
You just don't understand, do you?
This is the thing I desire the most!
Now you die!
Rai!
You fool!
Radar returns incoming!
Who?
My lord, it's the Tharsis and a UFE Cataphrat!
Those are...
Rai!
Three Direction Crossfire!
Target with multiple rounds!
Slay your fire control to me!
I hated it.
From when I first saw it, I hated it.
I hate that color!
Is that you, Sir Harklight?
The drones are all on autopilot!
Get behind the boulders!
We can limit the direction of their attack!
Attack!
Are you alright?
Mostly.
But I did lose one of my arms.
Sir Harklight!
Battle status?
Including myself, there are three Stygis Masters remaining with only six slave units.
The rest were taken down by the UFE.
I've used up most of my ammunition.
And you, Count Boracruz?
The right arm on Octantis is non-functional.
It must have been damaged during that last attack.
It seems Terran warriors are not without skill.
True.
It is, after all, where Lord Slane was born.
Yes, it is much like fighting a great sandstorm on Olympus.
It seems we may have misread the winds.
Let's do this.
I'm with you.
Enemy formation, nine o'clock!
Twenty degrees elevation!
All guns, lock on!
Cataphract platoon!
All units, fire at will!
Hmm.
All act as a drogue chute.
That will stabilize you.
Do you intend to die too?
You'll burn up.
Cataphract frames are very high density.
It should work as an ablation shield.
Impossible.
It can't be done.
Really?
Guess we'll see.
Sis, look!
There!
A shooting star.
That might be
Under the mountain helen in the desert.
And there it is.
Aldnoa Reactor 1, constructed as a sign of goodwill between Earth and Verse, is scheduled to be activated today.
We're told that Empress of Salem herself will take part in this inaugural activation ceremony.
Research is continuing into opening up the activation ability and privileges to everyone.
Once that is achieved, industrial use of Aldnoa will rapidly develop and help greatly with Earth's reconstruction.
As the sole provider of Aldnoa, it should also generate much needed capital for the Verse Empire.
The activation theories of Dr. Troyard have already been proven, so we should be seeing great progress.
That's true. Yet it is darkly ironic that slain Troyard, son of that same Dr. Troyard, plotted the assassination of Empress of Salem, which was the trigger for the second interplanetary war.
Yes, but the death of slain Troyard was the event which allowed Earth and Verse to enact a friendship treaty.
Correct. But there are still Mars Knights occupying Earth territory.
One goal of Empress of Salem's visit is peace negotiations with those Knights.
Here's hoping that we will see the prompt return of that territory.
In the clear hope that the light we create here will be a bridge of peace between Earth and Verse.
Awaken!
Thank you.
Feeling well?
You don't look that bad.
You could do a better job of eating your food, though.
The warden is getting concerned.
It's your move.
Your eye?
Hm?
Is that from when I shot you?
Analytical engine.
I had a bio device implanted in there.
It was neural linked to my cranial nerves.
But I had it removed.
Don't need it now.
Let me die.
I deceived.
I stole.
I killed.
I sacrificed many of my own.
Please.
Not yet.
You're going to live.
Why did you...
Why did you have to save me?!
I have one last favor to ask.
It wasn't for me.
It was for Princess of Salem.
Please.
Please save Slain.
Just save Slain Troyart is all that I ask.
Save him from the chains of misery.
Do that.
Salem wanted it.
She asked me to save you.
Let him die next.
Okay.
Jesus.
Lord exactly.
Is this me a friend of mine?
Well?
What?
Is this me a real person?
I waited for 30 years, but he wanted to bite.
It was beautiful.
I waited
my goodness the blue sea and sky they go on forever it's so beautiful i'm told the blue sky
is from something called rayleigh scattering you know quite a lot it was back when i was visiting
earth the last time a terra and i had befriended was kind enough to teach me
it's a lovely memory
yeah
So
so
I'm a star-spangled banner yet.
I'm just a star-spangled banner yet.
キミが夢見るなら when you're in the island,
同じ彼方へ 手を伸ばすよ.
キミが信じた静かな空に
I'll see you next time.